<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Leszek Karlik Translations</title>
    <link href="https://karlik-translations.github.io/karlik-translations/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://karlik-translations.github.io/karlik-translations" />
    <updated>2024-12-04T00:27:15+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Leszek Karlik</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://karlik-translations.github.io/karlik-translations</id>

    <entry>
        <title>PL</title>
        <author>
            <name>Leszek Karlik</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://karlik-translations.github.io/karlik-translations/doswiadczenie.html"/>
        <id>https://karlik-translations.github.io/karlik-translations/doswiadczenie.html</id>

        <updated>2024-12-04T00:24:07+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Leszek Karlik Translations zapewnia tłumaczenia techniczne, medyczne, ekonomiczne i prawne z angielskiego na polski i z polskiego na angielski, specjalizując się w szybkiej realizacji pilnie potrzebnych projektów. Bez problemu radzę sobie z krótkimi terminami i zawsze dostarczam tłumaczenia na czas. Tłumaczę od 1994, głównie teksty&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Leszek Karlik Translations zapewnia tłumaczenia techniczne, medyczne, ekonomiczne i prawne z angielskiego na polski i z polskiego na angielski, specjalizując się w szybkiej realizacji pilnie potrzebnych projektów. Bez problemu radzę sobie z krótkimi terminami i zawsze dostarczam tłumaczenia na czas.</p>
<p>Tłumaczę od 1994, głównie teksty techniczne (specjalizując się w energetyce, kolejnictwie, wyrobach medycznych, wnioskach patentowych oraz IT), później rozszerzyłem działalność na tłumaczenia prawne i ekonomiczne. Przykładowe tematy większych projektów tłumaczeniowych, w których brałem udział:</p>
<ul>
<li>IT (bezpieczeństwo komputerowe)</li>
<li>obiekty hydrotechniczne</li>
<li>infrastruktura gazu ziemnego</li>
<li>konserwacja i modernizacja zawodowych elektrowni węglowych</li>
<li>projekty energetyki wiatrowej</li>
<li>katalog rozdzielnic WN i SN oraz innych urządzeń przesyłowych</li>
<li>naprawa sprzętu wojskowego</li>
<li>konserwacja broni palnej</li>
<li>konserwacja i naprawa motocykli</li>
<li>SIWZ na wyposażenie do konserwacji torów kolejowych</li>
<li>urządzenia do cięcia plazmą</li>
<li>systemy przetwarzania żywności</li>
<li>urządzenia rolnicze</li>
<li>produkcja części samochodowych</li>
<li>wszczepialne kardiowertery-defibrylatory</li>
<li>urządzenia do monitorowania pacjentów</li>
<li>badania farmaceutyczne</li>
<li>epidemiologia</li>
<li>szczepionki mRNA</li>
<li>prawo pracy</li>
<li>… oraz niezliczone umowy, kontrakty itp.</li>
</ul>
<p>Tłumaczyłem, korygowałem i redagowałem różne artykuły naukowe publikowane później w angielskojęzycznych punktowanych czasopismach naukowych z zakresu medycyny, prawa i ekonomii.</p>
<p>Przetłumaczyłem polskie wydanie książki <em>Nowa bankowość spółdzielcza w Europie: strategie adaptacji modelu biznesowego </em>pod redakcją Marca Migliorelliego.</p>
<p>Mam tytuł magistra filologii angielskiej Uniwersytetu Warszawskiego, obroniłem pracę magisterską w 2008 roku.</p>
<p>Jestem tłumaczem przysięgłym języka angielskiego, wpisanym na listę tłumaczy przysięgłych, prowadzoną przez Ministra Sprawiedliwości pod nr TP/24/60, pracującym w Warszawie. Mogę również dostarczyć tłumaczenia poświadczone podpisane cyfrowym podpisem kwalifikowanym zgodnie z art. 18 ust. 1a Ustawy o zawodzie tłumacza przysięgłego z 2004 r.</p>
<p>Bardzo dobrze znam większość narzędzi CAT stosowanych na rynku. W codziennej pracy używam SDL Studio 2021, ale przetłumaczyłem również tysiące stron w MemoQ i bardzo dobrze znam Phrases (dawne Memsource). Dobrze znam środowiska desktopowe Windows i Linux oraz pakiety oprogramowania biurowego Microsoft Office i LibreOffice.</p>
<p>W wolnym czasie czytam literaturę SF, raporty IPCC oraz inne badania z pola klimatu i energetyki. W ramach hobby jeżdżę na rowerze, żegluję, windsurfuję i uprawiam strzelectwo sportowe.</p>
<p>Jestem członkiem Związku Zawodowego Tłumaczy Przysięgłych: <a href="https://www.zztp.pl/">https://www.zztp.pl/</a></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Dane kontaktowe:</p>
<p>E-mail: <a href="mailto:leszek.karlik@gmail.com">leszek.karlik@gmail.com</a> <br>Tel./WhatsApp: +48 453 127 914<br>Signal: tlumacz_przysiegly.97</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>EN</title>
        <author>
            <name>Leszek Karlik</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://karlik-translations.github.io/karlik-translations/leszek-karlik-translations.html"/>
        <id>https://karlik-translations.github.io/karlik-translations/leszek-karlik-translations.html</id>

        <updated>2024-12-04T00:21:43+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Leszek Karlik Translations provides technical, medical, economic, and legal translations from English to Polish and Polish to English, specialising in rapid delivery of urgently needed projects. I work well under tight deadlines, and I always meet them. I have been translating since 1994, mostly technical&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>Leszek Karlik Translations provides technical, medical, economic, and legal translations from English to Polish and Polish to English, specialising in rapid delivery of urgently needed projects. I work well under tight deadlines, and I always meet them.</p>
<p>I have been translating since 1994, mostly technical texts (specialising in power engineering, railway equipment, medical equipment, patent applications and IT), later branching to legal and economic translation. Some example topics of larger translation projects I have participated in include:</p>
<ul>
<li>IT (computer security)</li>
<li>hydrotechnical engineering</li>
<li>natural gas infrastructure</li>
<li>maintenance and refurbishment of coal power plants</li>
<li>wind power projects</li>
<li>a catalogue of HV and MV switchgears and transmission equipment</li>
<li>military hardware repair</li>
<li>firearm maintenance</li>
<li>motorcycle maintenance and repair</li>
<li>invitation to tender for railway maintenance equipment</li>
<li>plasma cutting equipment</li>
<li>food processing</li>
<li>agricultural machinery</li>
<li>manufacturing of automotive parts</li>
<li>implantable cardioverter-defibrillator</li>
<li>patient monitoring devices</li>
<li>pharmaceutical research</li>
<li>epidemiology</li>
<li>mRNA vaccines</li>
<li>employment law</li>
<li>… and countless agreements, contracts and so on.</li>
</ul>
<p>I have translated, proofread and edited various academic papers published in English-language peer-reviewed medical, legal and economic journals.</p>
<p>I’m the translator of the Polish edition of <em>New Cooperative Banking in Europe: Strategies for Adapting the Business Model Post Crisis</em>, edited by Marco Migliorelli (published in Poland as <em>Nowa bankowość spółdzielcza w Europie: strategie adaptacji modelu biznesowego</em>).</p>
<p>I have a Master of Arts degree from the English department of the University of Warsaw, majoring in British literature with a minor in English linguistics, graduating in 2008.</p>
<p>I’m a sworn translator registered on the list of sworn translators of the Minister for Justice under No TP/24/60, working in Warsaw. I can also provide sworn translations signed with a qualified digital signature, in accordance with Article 18(1a) of the 2004 Act on the Profession of the Sworn Translator.</p>
<p>I am well-versed with most CAT tools used on the market. I use SDL Studio 2021 in my daily work, but I also translated thousands of pages in MemoQ and I’m very familiar with Phrases (formerly Memsource) and XTM. I’m also proficient with Windows and Linux desktop environments and Microsoft Office and LibreOffice software.</p>
<p>In my spare time I read sci-fi literature interspersed with IPCC reports and other climate and energy policy papers. I also bike, sail, windsurf and shoot handguns.</p>
<p>I’m a member of the Polish Sworn Translators Trade Union: <a href="https://www.zztp.pl/">https://www.zztp.pl/</a></p>
<p><strong>Contact info:</strong></p>
<p>E-mail: <a href="mailto:leszek.karlik@gmail.com">leszek.karlik@gmail.com</a> <br>Phone/WhatsApp: +48 453 127 914<br>Signal: tlumacz_przysiegly.97</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
